准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
船不能白搭
导演
分镜
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
我们又来到了裤头村滑浪学校
Here we are again at the Bikini Bottom Boating School
今天又是海绵宝宝进行驾考的日子
Today is once again
the day of SpongeBob's boating school exam
但更重要的是
but more importantly
这是今年最后一次驾考
this is the last test for the year
如果海绵宝宝这次驾考又挂了
and if SpongeBob does not pass this one
就表示他又要再上一整年的驾校
it means another whole year of boating school
怎么了
Wha' happen?
没什么  海绵宝宝
Nothing, SpongeBob
你只是又撞上了个行人
You just struck another pedestrian
再扣二十分
Minus 20 more points
我还剩多少分
How many does that leave me with?
负224分
Negative 224
我驾考还剩多少分钟
How many more minutes left in the test?
已经考完了
The test is over
时间还很充裕
That's enough time
扣的分还能补回来
I can make up those points
不
No
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
等等
Wait
你没听清楚
You didn't hear me
已经太迟了
It's too late
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
好  泡芙老师
Okay, Mrs. Puff
我最终成绩有多少
what's my final score?
六
Six
要多少分才能过
And how many do I need to pass?
六
Six
百
Hundred
什么
Wha?
六百
Six hundred
要考六百才能过
You need 600 to pass
你才六分
You got six
你放心
Don't worry
我不会气馁的  泡芙老师
I'll be all right, Mrs. Puff
并且
Besides
这就表示我还要再上你的课
This means I get to be in your class
整整一年
for a whole 'nother year
下周二再见
Well, see you next Tuesday
滑浪学校
好耶
Yeah
我要领到驾照了
I'm gonna get my driver's license
只要再上一整年
and it's only gonna take one more year
一整年
one more year
超级无敌一整年
One more super-duper year
超级无敌精彩绝伦
One more super-spectacular
神神奇奇完美一整年
extra-magical, extra-fantastical year
海神王啊
Oh, Neptune
又要跟他耗一年
Another year with him
真见鬼
Barnacles
又该死又见鬼
Dirty barnacles
一定要做点自保措施
I've got to do something to save myself
只有一个办法
there's only one way out
老师的杀手锏
A teacher's ace in the hole
额外加分
Extra credit
你说什么  泡芙老师
What was that, Mrs. Puff?
额外加分  海绵宝宝
Extra credit, SpongeBob
额外加分
The extra credit
我还有机会
I still have a chance
我  我是说
I, I mean
你还有机会
you still have a chance
什么是额外加分
What's extra credit?
就是可以获得
It's when you get credit
以前你不会做的事情的对应的学分
for the things you weren't able to do before
滑浪学校
准备好额外加分了没
Now, are we ready for that extra credit?
额外加分
Extra credit
这样就对了
That's the spirit
你要是想
So, all you have to do
领到额外加分  过了我的课
to earn your extra credit and pass my class
再也不用靠近这所学校
and never have to
come anywhere near this school again
就只要写句十个字的句子
is write a ten-word sentence
主题是你在滑浪学校学到的知识
on what you've learned in boating school
可我学了好多知识
But I've learned so many things
随便选一个  选哪个我不管
Just pick one, I don't care which
来  我替你开头
Here, I'll help you get started
我在驾校里学了
"What I learned in boating school is"
好了
There
已经七个字了
That's already seven words
只要再写三个
Only three more
学
L-E-A-R
真见鬼
Barnacles
怎么了
What's wrong?
得先削铅笔
Got to sharpen my pencil
了
N-E
快给我
Give me that
给你钢笔
Here's a pen
钢笔
A pen
经典永流传的书写用具之一
One of the most permanent of all writing utensils
要去写作文
Gonna write an essay
就是要这样
That's what I say
好了
There
太棒了
Fantastic
让我看看
Let me see it
不  等等
No, wait
我反悔了
I changed my mind
不管你写的什么都不会有事的
I'm sure whatever you've written it's fine
让我看看
Just let me see
别看
No, don't look
还没好
It's not ready
很简单的
It's so simple
只要十个字
Only ten words
我在驾校里学了
"What I learned in boating school is"
填空
Blankety
blankety
空
blank
我能行的
I can do this
我在驾校里学了
"What I learned in boating school is"
我能行的
I can do this
里面感觉好热  泡芙老师
Is it hot in here, Mrs. Puff?
为什么里面这么热
Why is it so hot in here?
我的手
My hand
我的手抽筋了  泡芙老师
My hand is cramping, Mrs. Puff
快停下
Make it stop
你只要再写
You only need
三
three
个字
more words
好
Okay
我看看你写的句子
let me see what you've written
还没写好
It's not ready yet
没事  海绵宝宝
That's okay, SpongeBob
给老师看看你写的句子
Show the teacher what you've written
不行
No
快给我
Give it to me
不行
No
给我看
Let me see it
我在驾校里学了
"What I learned in boating school is"
剩下的都不重要
Well, the rest doesn't matter
你过了
You pass
泡芙老师  我感觉我什么都没做
Mrs. Puff, I don't feel like I really did anything
额外加分本来就得这种感觉
That's how extra credit is supposed to feel
真的吗
Really?
另外这是你的驾照
Besides, here's your license
裤头村驾照
海绵宝宝
我的驾照
My license
宛如我梦中的滋味
It tastes just like I dreamt it would
泡芙老师  我
Mrs. Puff, I
谢谢你  海绵宝宝
Thank you, SpongeBob
恭喜你了
Congratulations
好人一生平安
Have a nice life
小心了  裤头村
Look out, Bikini Bottom
有个新司机要上路了
There's a new driver on the road
他就叫做
and his name is
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
哈里斯  生日快乐
Harris, happy birthday
我的腿
My leg
破坏竟会如此之多
So much destruction
直播
记者不禁要问为什么
This reporter asks why
本地舆论一致认为问题出在
Local consensus places the blame
这位失职又自私的驾校教练身上
on this negligent selfish driving instructor
她
who
这段别播出来
Let's not use that take
太荒唐了
That's preposterous
他都额外加分了
He did the extra credit
没什么好怕的
There's no need to worry
他连船都没得开
He doesn't even have a boat to drive
现在回家去  把面都吃完
Now to go home and have the rest of that pasta
感谢泡芙老师
惊喜
Surprise
敬史上最棒的老师
To the greatest teacher ever
谢谢泡芙老师
Thank you, Mrs. Puff
我在此说出大家的心声
I know I speak for everyone
我们要把你当作
when I say that we consider you
海绵家族的一员
a member of the SquarePants family
你该说的都说完了  亲爱的
I think you've made your point, dear
泡芙老师  本来我们还以为
Mrs. Puff, we were starting to think
海绵宝宝绝对考不到驾照
SpongeBob was never going to get his license
但你从来没放弃过他
But you never gave up on him
从来没打退堂鼓
You never quit
从来没应付了事
You never took the easy way out
那个  我
Well, I, uh
好吧
okay
我们只想让泡芙老师
We wanted to make sure Mrs. Puff--
全世界最好的驾校老师
the greatest driving teacher in the world--
能来亲眼目睹这个
was here to see this
目睹什么
See what?
哒哒
Ta-da
我准备好了
裤头村
"I-M R-DY"
全新汽船
A brand new boatmobile?
给我的
For me?
你放心  泡芙老师
Don't worry, Mrs. Puff
他明天就能开了
He'll be driving by tomorrow
再见
Toodle-oo
我都干了什么好事
What have I done?
这下大家都要知道
Everyone will know
是我放他毕业的了
that I let him slide through school
我必须搬去另外的城市
I'll have to move to a new city
另外开所驾校  另外取个名字
start a new boating school with a new name
不
No
不能再这样了
not again
必须把苗头遏制住
I've got to end this thing before it begins
你摔得挺重的  儿子
You took quite a buster there, son
我今天在驾校里学了
What I learned in boating school today is
我们还是先放一放
We're going to have to hold off
开船的事情  儿子
on the driving there for a while, son
没错  乖儿子
That's right, honey
在床上躺好
Now, just stay in bed
不要靠近船
And no going near the boat
嗨  小船
Hi, Boaty
小船  你着凉了
Boaty, you're cold
穿我袜子吧
Take my socks
小船  我会把你照顾好的
Oh, Boaty, I'm always going to take care of you
你是全海底最好的船了
You're the best boat in the deep blue sea
希望我还记得怎么做
I hope I still remember how to do this
好
Yeah
我在开船
I'm driving
你是谁  在我船上干什么
Who are you and what are you doing in my boat?
为什么戴着滑雪面罩
And why are you wearing that ski mask?
你压根就没滑雪
Because you're not skiing
我的天啊  我知道你是谁了
Oh, my gosh, I know who you are
不知道
No, you don't
你根本就不认识我
You don't know who I am
认得可清楚了
Yes, I do
我知道你是
I know that you're
偷船贼
a boatjacker
我居然得用到这瓶胡椒喷雾
I never thought I'd have to use this pepper spray
来人救命啊
Somebody help me
抱歉  海绵宝宝
Sorry, SpongeBob
这都是为了你好
but it was for your own good
把船还给我
Give me back my boat
给我停船
You'd better stop this boat
我不会放手的
I'm not letting go
什么都阻止不了我
Nothing will stop me
哪怕有
Not even
巨蚌
Giant clams?
我绝不放手  哪怕有
I'm not letting go even for
奶酪擦
Cheese graters?
不
No
休想让我放手  哪怕路上有
If you think I'll let go for a little
教育电视台
Educational television?
不要啊
Oh, no
看来甩掉他了
Looks like that got rid of him
放点音乐
Now for some tunes
现在回到人渣电台
And now back to KRUD
接下来为你点播
with all of your personal
你偷我车绝对要受制裁  金曲
"You won't get away with stealing my car" hits
出事故请拨打
超级警察
看
Look
我绝对不会让你偷到船的
I'd never let you have this boat
就算你是
Not even if you were
泡芙老师
Mrs. Puff?
那你还好吗  泡芙老师
So, how's it going, Mrs. Puff?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
我想
I'd like to
道个歉
apologize
我不该让你过的
I shouldn't have passed you
你还没准备好
You really weren't ready
所以我得把驾照还回去吗
So, I guess I got to give my license back, huh?
听说比目鱼老师
I hear Mrs. Flounder
新开了一节周一早上的班
is starting a new class Monday morning
开什么玩笑
You kidding?
我只有你才配教
You're the only teacher for this student
并且狱长说她会早点放你走
And besides, the warden says she'll let you go early
只要你帮人家忙
if you do her a favor
什么忙
What's that?
裤头村监狱
免费驾驶课
Free driving lessons
头号粉丝
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
分镜总监
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
欢迎各位水母迷
不敢相信
I can't believe it
我们来到了
We're actually here
一年两度的捉水母大会
at the biannual Jellyfish Convention
捉水母就是好
Jellyfish are awesome
实用水母网
世界一流水母网
Cool state-of-the-art jellyfish nets
摸一下
Touch
不许摸
Don't touch
被蜇就用凯文药膏
凯文的最爱
捉水母大电影里的水母叉
The harpoon from Jellyfish: The Movie
摸一下
Touch
不许摸
Don't touch
看
Look
僧帽博士
Dr. Manowar
他被大兰尼蜇了都还能幸存下来
The guy who got stung by Big Lenny and lived
这个大包只有摸了才会疼
And now it only hurts when you touch it
摸一下
Touch
非得我整天跟着你吗
Do I have to follow you all day?
派大星  快看
Patrick, look
不会吧
Can it be?
冰淇淋
Ice cream?
不对  是水母捕手
No, it's The Jellyspotters
水母捕手
裤头村顶级水母迷俱乐部
Bikini Bottom's premiere jellyfish enthusiasts club
还有他们的社长
And their leader
史上最酷的水母迷
the coolest jellyfish enthusiast ever
海参凯文
Kevin the Sea Cucumber
书呆海黄瓜有什么意思
What's so great about a nerdy pickle?
如果我能摸到他袖珍笔袋的褶边
If I could just touch the hem of his pocket protector
那我大概就可以沾点他的光了
then maybe some of his greatness would rub off on me
海绵宝宝  身为你朋友
SpongeBob, as a friend
我得说那太书呆了
I must say that's really geeky
我的天啊
Oh, my gosh
水母杰弗里
Jeffrey Jellyfish
别走  杰弗里
Wait, Jeffrey
我要摸摸你
I have to touch you
竹子
Bamboo?
我网柄只用复合材料
I only use composite materials in my net handle
复合材料
Composite materials
下一个问题
Next question
嗨  凯文
Hi, Kevin
嗨
Hi
你有什么问题
What is your question?
嗨  凯文
Hi, Kevin
随便你
Whatever
请问下一个问题
Next question, please?
嗨  凯文
Hi, Kevin
你好  废物
Hello, loser
好  后边那位提问
All right, you way in the back
嗨  凯文
Hi, Kevin
这边有谁是真心想问
Does anyone here have an actual
嗨  凯文
Hi, Kevin
我是你的头号粉丝
I'm your biggest fan
你真好心
You're too kind
保安
Security
不  等等
No, wait
我什么都可以给你做
I would do anything for you
不然你就跳楼好了
Why don't you go jump off a building?
什么都可以
Anything
用拳头打自己脸
Punch yourself in the face
你那样没伤着吧
Doesn't that hurt you?
要我把自己伤着吗  凯文
Do you want it to hurt me, Kevin?
这样最好了
That is the best
这家伙挺好
This guy's great
一定要带这位一起来捉水母
We have got to bring this guy jellyfishing with us
不行  凯文
No, Kevin, no
他是怪才
He's a geek
听好  我不会让他加入俱乐部的
Look, I won't let the guy join the club
我只想看他要让水母蜇多少次
I just want to see how many times he can get stung
才会哭哭啼啼跑回家去
before he goes running home like a baby
凯文是天才
Kevin's a genius
天才
Genius
凯文
Kevin
小子
Hey, kid
想不想参加水母捕手的选拔测试
How would you like to try out for The Jellyspotters?
离床
Clear
我想
I'd love it
来水母田开敞篷兜风最舒服了
Nothing like driving through jellyfish fields
with the top down
对吧  水母捕手
eh, Jellyspotters?
敞篷
Top down
水母田
我们到了
Well, here we are
水母田
Jellyfish Fields
希望你网没忘带
I hope you didn't forget our nets
我没忘带  凯文
I didn't forget them, Kevin
都在后备箱里
They're in the trunk
我居然会跟水母捕手一起来这
I can't believe I'm here with The Jellyspotters
我一生都想成为水母捕手的一员
I mean all my life I wanted to be a Jellyspotter
我现在带着网和罐子跟你过来了
and now I'm here with you guys with the nets and the jars
我跟凯文在一起  和大家聚在一起
and I'm with Kevin and Kevin's with me
大家齐聚一堂
and we're all with each other
一起捉水母  超级有趣的
and we're jellyfishing together and it's fun and
停
Hold it
在你加入水母捕手之前
Before you become a Jellyspotter
必须先通过严格的测试
you have to pass a rigorous test
严格的测试
rigorous test
安静
Quiet
你的第一项测试
Your first test?
捉一只水母
Catch a jellyfish
捉到一只了
I caught one
我加入水母捕手了吗
Am I a Jellyspotter now?
他抓到了
he caught one
加入俱乐部
in the club
那只不算
No, that doesn't count
我是说两只水母
I meant two jellyfish
两只水母
Two jellyfish
进网了
in the net
我不是那意思
That's not what I meant
我是说二十只水母
I meant 20 jellyfish
我数数
Let's see
一二三
One, two, three
水母捕手会让水母吃脸上的水母酱
Jellyspotters allow jellyfish
to eat jelly off their face
谁想来舔我脸颊
Who wants to lick my cheeks?
有水母来吃了
I see I have some takers
感觉如何
How does it feel?
鼻子好痒
It tickles my nose
痒不久了
Not for long
能不能别叫了
Will you cut that out?
我现在加入水母捕手了吗
Am I in The Jellyspotters now?
不
No
你还有好几项测试
I have many more tests for you to take
我现在加入水母捕手了吗
Am I in The Jellyspotters now?
不
No
我现在加入水母捕手了吗
Am I in The Jellyspotters now?
不
No
现在呢
Now?
不
No
现在呢
Now?
不
No
现在呢
Now?
不
No
现在呢
Now?
好了  海绵宝宝
Okay, SquarePants
现在到你让水母电了
It is your turn to get zapped
我是说
I mean
准备好进行最后一项测试了吗
are you ready for your final test?
我准备好了
I'm ready
最好是好了
You'd better be
因为我们要抓的是水母皇后
because we're going to capture a queen jellyfish
皇后
A queen
我能帮忙吗
Can I help?
放心
Don't worry
没有你  我们做不到
We can't do it without you
真是太棒了
This is fantastic
我从来没当过诱饵
I've never been bait before
我也没见过水母皇后
I don't think I've ever seen a queen jellyfish either
那你大概就没用过
Well, then you've probably never used
水母皇后哨了
a queen jellyfish call
你先试试看好不好
Why don't you try it out?
废物
Loser
我以前听过这种哨音
I've heard this call before
你肯定听过
I'll bet you have
你们要去哪
Where you going?
放心好了
Don't worry
我们就在灌木丛后头
We'll be right behind this bush
谁带了我的蜇伤药膏
Who's got my sting ointment?
太好了
This is great
等我通过测试了
When I pass this test
我就能正式加入水母捕手了
I'll be an official jellyfish spotter
废物
Loser
凯文
Hey, Kevin
哨子好像没什么用
I don't think it's working
无事发生
Nothing
凯文  皇后来了
Kevin, she's here
快看
Look
快看  皇后来了
Look, she's here
皇后来了  凯文
She's here, Kevin
皇后
she's
凯文药膏
求你别生气  皇后
Please don't be angry, your highness
我会放你走的
I would have let you go
凯文
Kevin
没错
That's right
你应该看看我们电你那时候
You should have seen the look on your face
你脸上的表情
when we zapped you
可
But
我最后一项测试呢
what about my final test?
你不会真以为
Did you think
我们真会让你加入水母捕手吧
we'd actually let youjoin The Jellyspotters?
可是  凯文
But, Kevin
我是你的头号粉丝
I was your biggest fan
他们也是
So were they
大家快看
Look, everybody
凯文回来了
Kevin's back
凯文
Kevin
我们爱你  凯文
We love you, Kevin
凯文  拜托
Kevin, please
你样子笨死了
You looked so dumb
还吹笨得要死的水母哨
with your dorky jellyfish call
废物
Loser
我不是废物
I am not a loser
废物
Loser
刺胞霸王
Nideria rex
水母国王
King Jellyfish
亲亲脸
Kissyface
被蜇就用凯文药膏
凯文的最爱
凯文
Kevin
它好像走了
I think he's gone
你们哪位出去打探一下
One of you go out and check
救命
Save us
凯文
Kevin
救命
save us
别看我
Don't look at me
我为了追赶潮流才加入的
I was just in this for the fashion
水母
没希望了
It's hopeless
我们被困住了
We're trapped
救命  妈妈
Help me, Mommy
救命
help me
我要小毯毯
I want my blanky
现在该怎么办
Now what do we do?
妈妈
Mommy
救命  妈妈
Help, Mommy
妈妈
Mommy
怎么
What the?
美味
Yummy
不敢相信
I can't believe it
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
大家都爱吃派
Everybody loves pie
海绵宝宝  实在是太强了
Well, SquarePants, that was impressive
但你还是不能加入俱乐部
but you're still not in the club
因为你没捉到水母皇后
because you didn't catch a queen jellyfish
等等
Wait
你们干什么
What are you doing?
我都不知道这个原来是帽子
I didn't know this was a hat
才不是
It wasn't
嗨  派大星
Hi, Patrick
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
你加入俱乐部了吗
Did you get into that club?
本来想  不过后来还是拒绝了
Yeah, but I turned them down
不是为凯文
It's not about Kevin
是为了水母
It's about jellyfish
海绵宝宝  很高兴你学到教训了
SpongeBob, I'm glad you learned your lesson
崇拜偶像不健康
Hero worship is unhealthy
走了  杰弗里
Come on, Jeffrey